Up until this point you've been launching nodes using the venerable Rosrun command.
ここまでに 優れた rosrun コマンドを使用して複数のノードを起動してきました
As I mentioned previously,
以前触れたように
a Ros system usually consists of many running nodes.
ROS システムは通常 多くの実行ノードから構成されています
Running all of the nodes by hand though can be torturous.
すべてのノードを手動で実行するのは大変な手間がかかります
This is where the roslaunch command comes to save the day.
roslaunch コマンドはそうした面倒を解決してくれます
Roslaunch allows you to launch multiple nodes with one simple command,
roslaunch コマンドを使用すると 1 つの簡単なコマンドで複数のノードを起動する
set default parameters in the pram server,
パラメータサーバのデフォルト値を設定する
automatically respond processes that have died and more.
停止(死んでいる)しているプロセスを自動実行することができます
To use roslaunch, you must first make
roslaunch を使用するには まずワークスペースを構築し
sure that your work space has been built and sourced.
このワークスペースをソースにする必要があります
Recall, to build the work space,
思い出してください ワークスペースを構築するには
you use the command catkin_make while you're in the root of the work space.
ワークスペースのルート内から catkin_make コマンドを使用します
So, let's move to the root of the work space
ワークスペースのルートに移動しましょう
and let's issue the build command, catkin_make.
それから構築コマンド catkin_make を発行します
Once the work space has been built,
ワークスペースが構築されたら
you can source its set up script.
その setup スクリプトを使います
The set up script lives in
setup スクリプトは ワークスペースのルート内に
the newly created directory devel in the root of the work space.
新しく作成されたディレクトリ devel 内にあります
In the same fashion as the setup.bash script in the OPT Ros directory,
OPT Ros ディレクトリ内の setup.bash スクリプトと同じ方法で
the work space is setup.bash is responsible for setting up the environment variables,
ワークスペースの setup.bash は 環境変数のセットアップを行います
which are responsible for letting the system find all of the packages,
これは 使用する catkin ワークスペースから提供されるすべてのパッケージ
libraries and other resources provided by your catkin work space.
ライブラリ その他リソースをシステムによって検出させるものです
So let's go ahead and source that now.
では 先へ進めてこれをソースしましょう
With your work space sourced,
ソースしたワークスペースで
you can now launch simple arm.
simple_arm を起動します
To do so, use the command roslaunch,
これを行うにはコマンド roslaunch を使用します
followed by the package name rossimple_arm and then the name of the launch file.
その後にパッケージ名　simple_arm  その次に起動ファイル名を続けて指定します
And here, I'm just going to use tab completion robot_spawn.launch.
ここはタブ完了の robot_spawn.launch を使用します
Awesome. There we go. I've launched the arm
素晴らしいご覧のとおりですlaunch ファイルと simple_arm パッケージを
using the launch file and the simple arm package.
使用して arm を起動しました
A number of things just happened.
いくつかのことが起こりました
Perhaps the most apparent is that,
すぐにわかるのは
I now have a robotic arm running in simulation.
シミュレーション内で実行するロボットアームがあることです
The simulator is called gazebo.
このシミュレーターは Gazebo といいます
You continue to use it many times throughout this program.
このプログラム内ではこれを引き続き使用していきます
It is our surrogate for the real world,
これを実世界として代用し
it's responsible for simulating forces and torques,
各種の力やトルク 時間の経過
the passage of time,
衝突などのオブジェクト間の
as well as interactions between objects such as collisions.
相互作用をシミュレートします
The robot I'm simulating here is a simple two degree of freedom robotic arm.
ここでシミュレートするロボットは 簡単な 2 自由度制御系ロボットアームです
It's perhaps hard to tell but there is a little black ball on the end of the arm.
見えにくいかもしれませんが アームの先端には小さな黒いボールがついています
The ball represents a camera.
このボールはカメラを表します
Gazebo can also simulate a wide variety of sensors.
Gazeboでは多様なセンサーもシミュレートできます
It's not just gazebo that's running though.
実行されているのは Gazebo だけではありません
If you switch over to the console window and scroll up,
コンソールウィンドウに切り替えて上にスクロールすると
you can see that roslaunch has provided
roslaunch から起動したすべてのノードと
the brief summary of all of the nodes which have been launched,
設定したすべてのパラメーターの
and all of the parameters which have been set.
概要が簡単にまとめられています
I won't spend any time talking about all the details of
launch ファイルについてすべての詳細を紹介したりはしませんが
the launch file here but I encourage you to check it out.
内容の確認はお勧めします
It's in the launch directory within the simple arm package.
このファイルは simple_arm パッケージ内の launch ディレクトリにあります
Now, that you understand how to create a work space,
さて ワークスペースを作成し パッケージを追加し
add a package, build and launch everything,
あれこれを構築し起動する方法を説明しました
you're prepared for the next step,
これで次のステップに進む準備ができました
figuring out why the arm is just swinging around loosely in simulation.
シミュレーション内でアームが振り子のように揺れている理由を解き明かしましょう
While I'll be explaining it thoroughly in the next section,
次のセクションで詳しく説明しますが
I encourage you to try to figure it out before I spill the beans.
その前に自分でも考えてみてください
Here's a hint. Check the log messages in the ros master console.
ヒントを出しますROS マスターコンソールのログメッセージをチェックしましょう